Basically all of them are powered by electric, and they have an on and off switch, and a foot pedal, of course.
One important thing about this, is so you don't hurt yourself, is it operates just like a car.
You press down to go - the wheel head goes faster, down to stop.
Before you ever turn your wheel on, you always want to make sure that your heel is down before you turn it on.
If it's not, if you have it on, and you have some things sitting on it, and you turn it on, a chair, a bucket, it will scare you.
Plus you might hurt yourself.
So always make sure that the heel is down before you turn it on.
They all have an on and off switch.
Now some potters wheel features, if you're left handed, the potters wheel actually goes clockwise, okay?
The other types of wheel there are is - this is called the kick wheel, and this is for obvious reasons.
This was one of my first wheels.
You sit down on it, and you kick it as fast as you can.
I like this wheel because, as you can see, it has a half circle, a little shelf here, and I can get all my tools out around here.
It's easy to clean up - it's stainless steel, nothing rusts on it, and as you can see the wheel goes around and around, it will go around forever.
It has really nice ball bearings.
Splash pans - it has a really nice, easy splash pan to take off and on.
Danger part about these is that as the wheel's going, down here where you kick it, if you step on that, it will throw you for a loop!
So there are dangers - it's fun, but there are dangers, so you always want to stop your kick wheel before you get up and go.